Gentlemen, I think I've come up with a fun way...
Messieurs, j'ai trouvé un moyen amusant
...to get young people interested in science.
d'attirer les jeunes vers la science.
Physics Mad Libs.
Les maths amusantes.
Now, give me a number.
Donne—moi un chiffre.
-Five. -Uh-huh.
Cinq.
And an irrational constant.
Une constante irrationnelle.
And a funny Greek letter.
Une lettre grecque amusante.
Gamma.
Gamma.
I said funny.
J'ai dit ”amusante".
-Upsilon? -Heh, good one.
- Epsilon ? - Parfait.
And an electrical charge.
Et une charge électrique.
-Positive. -Ha, ha! Perfect.
- Positif. - Parfait.
Okay, get this. Ahem.
Ça donne.
"Professor Jones told the symposium...
"Le professeur Jones a dit au symposium
...he had a new method for calculating the mass of a muon.
qu'il avait trouvé une nouvelle méthode pour calculer la masse.
Five times the limit of, heh...
Cinq fois la limite
...E to the upsilon as it approaches--"
de E sur epsilon en tant que…
Ha, ha, oh, my gosh. Okay.
D‘accord.
I'll start over.
Je recommence.
"Professor Jo--"
"Le professeur..."
I haven't seen him laugh that hard...
Je ne l‘avais pas vu autant rire
...since the day Leonard made that multiplication error.
depuis le jour où Leonard s‘est trompé en multipliant.
Oh, Lord, that multiplication error.
Mon Dieu, cette erreur.
He thought he carried the one, but he didn't.
Il croyait qu'il avait trouvé la solution mais non.
It's not funny. That mistake got published.
Ça va. Ça a été publié.
Stop, I'm gonna wet myself.
Arrête. Je vais me faire dessus.
Guys. Guys, President Seibert is headed this way.
Le président Seibert Vient vers nous.
HOWARD: I wonder what he wants. -He doesn't look happy.
- Que veut-il ? - Il a l‘air furieux.
So I'm guessing he wants Sheldon.
Alors, c‘est pour Sheldon.
-Dr. Cooper. -Told you.
- Dr. Cooper. - Je l‘avais dit.
SHELDON: Ah, President Seibert.
Président.
I assume you'd like to respond...
Je suppose que vous voulez
...to one of the suggestions I put in the box by your office.
me parler des suggestions dans ma boîte à suggestions.
No, and stop installing suggestion boxes everywhere.
Non. Et arrêtez d'en installer partout.
You don't like written suggestions.
Pas par écrit.
You don't like when I give them to you while in the men's room.
Pas dans les toilettes.
If I didn't know any better, I'd say you're one of those people...
Si je ne vous connaissais pas, je dirais que
...who are not open to suggestions.
vous n‘aimez pas les suggestions.
Dr. Cooper, the Physics Department tells me you're refusing to take vacation.
Le département me dit que vous refuse: vos vacances.
-I don't need a vacation. -You're obligated to take one.
- En effet. - C‘est obligatoire.
And I'd like you to know the most often received suggestion...
La suggestion qui revient le plus souvent
...in my suggestion box you installed without asking me is:
dans votre boîte à suggestions est :
"Can Dr. Cooper take a vacation?"
"Le Dr. Cooper doit partir en vacances."
Okay, it's settled, then. I'll see you all on Monday. Except for you.
C‘est réglé. Je vous vois lundi. Sauf vous.
But if I don't come into work, what am I supposed to do?
Mais qu'est-ce que je suis censé faire ?
Read, rest, travel.
Lire, vous reposer, voyager.
I hear Afghanistan is nice this time of year.
L'Afghanistan, c‘est la bonne saison.
Sarcasm?
Sarcasme ?
No, you should go.
Non, tu devrais y aller.
Would you stop that caterwauling?
Tu peux arréter ce miaulement ?
What the hell are you doing?
Que fais-tu la ?
Bleeding from my ears.
Je saigne des oreilles.
-What are you doing hiding back there? -l'm sneaking into work.
- Que fais-tu caché ici ? - Je vais au travail.
Now, if the guard at the university asks what's under the blanket...
Si le gardien te demande ce que tu as sur le siège,
...you tell him it's some lobster traps.
tu réponds : "des pièges à homards".
-Lobster traps? -Yes.
- A homards ? - Oui.
That's how Velma and Scooby smuggled Shaggy into the old lighthouse.
Véra et Scooby ont fait comme ça pour faire passer Samy.
What are you gonna do when you get to the university?
Que vas-tu faire a l'université ?
People are going to recognize you.
On va te reconnaître.
Will they, Leonard?
Tu crois, Leonard ?
Fine. Just get back under your blanket and I'll drive you there.
D‘accord. Recouche-toi etje te conduis.
And no more singing.
Et plus de chant.
SHELDON: l have GPS on my phone. I know you turned around.
J'ai un GPS sur mon téléphone. Tu as fait demi—tour.
I'm so glad you talked Howard...
C‘est bien d‘avoir convaincu
...out of having your wedding invitations in Klingon.
Howard d‘oublier Ie Klingon pour les faire—part.
Turn it over.
Tourne—le.
I'm hoping my relatives think it's Hebrew.
Ma famille pensera que c‘est de l'hébreu.
This is really happening.
C‘est donc réel.
I'm gonna be a maid of honor.
Je vais être témoin.
I'm gonna wear a beautiful dress and walk down that aisle...
J‘aurai une belle robe, je descendrai l'allée.
...and finally, I will have my special day.
Ce sera majournée.
You mean my special day.
Tu veux dire, la mienne.
They're gonna need an extra-large veil for somebody's head.
Il va falloir un voile extra-large.
-lfl actually ever get married. -Why wouldn't you?
- Si je me marie. - Pourquoi pas ?
My dad. Because I make a lot more money than Howie...
Mon père. Je gagne plus d'argent qu‘Howie
...he's putting a lot of pressure on me to get a prenup.
et il veut que je fasse un contrat de mariage.
I remember the battle with my mother about shaving my legs.
Ma mère insistait pour que je me rase les jambes.
Last year, I finally gave in and let her do it.
L'an dernier, j'ai fini par céder.
ljust don't know how I'm gonna break it to him.
J'ignore comment lui annoncer.
I'm a believer in breaking bad news to a guy when you're in bed.
J‘adore annoncer ce genre de choses au lit.
That's how I told my high school boyfriend I slept with his brother.
Au lycée, j'ai dit a mon copain que je couchais avec son frère.
That's how I told his brother the same thing.
Et inversement.
I don't know. I don't wanna manipulate him with sex.
Je ne veux pas le manipuler par le sexe.
Oh, sweetie, that's what sex is for.
Le sexe, ça sert a ça.
The connection between marriage and money is nothing new.
Le lien entre le mariage et l'argent est réel.
The term "wed" referred to the money and livestock...
Cela fait référence à l'argent et au bétail
...the groom paid the bride's father.
que le marié doit payer.
For example, you're adorable, intelligent and a good earner.
Par exemple, tu es adorable, intelligente et riche.
I could conservatively see you going for at least two oxen and a goose.
Je te vois bien partir pour deux bœufs et une oie.
Sheldon, there are a million great vacations you could take.
Tu pourrais passer de superbes vacances.
What about Hawaii?
Hawaï, non ?
Hawaii is a former leper colony on top of an active volcano...
Hawaï est une ancienne colonie de lépreux sur un volcan
...where the disappointing ending to Lostwas filmed.
où la triste fin de Los! a été filmée.
Mahalo for nothing, Hawaii.
Non mahalo, Hawaï.
How about Florida?
Et la Floride ?
They got Cape Canaveral, they got Disney.
Il y a Cap Canaveral, Disney.
They got my Aunt Ida and the world's largest collection of diabetic candy.
Ma tante Ida et la plus grande collection de bonbons.
And plus, if you get sweaty enough...
Et si tu transpires assez,
...her plastic-covered furniture is like a flume ride.
son meuble devient un toboggan.
My family took a trip to Florida when l was a child.
Enfant, je suis déjà allé en Floride.
A seagull stole a hot dog from me on the beach.
Une mouette m‘a volé mon hot—dog sur la plage.
I got the message.
C‘était un message.
If I had a week off...
Si j‘avais des vacances,
...l'd go back to the Two Bunch Palms Resort and Spa in the desert.
je retournerais au spa Les Palmiers dans le désert.
I tell you, an hour on the massage table with Trevor...
Après une heure de massage avec Trevor,
...and you'll feel like you were born without bones.
tu te sentiras comme un nouveau-né sans os.
I don't think I could ever let a guy give me a massage.
Aucun homme ne me massera.
Really? What was I doing to your neck last night while you were playing Xbox?
Etje faisais quoi hier pendant que tu jouais àla console ?
Guys, I am living in a dictatorship.
Je vis sous une dictature.
[IN DEEP VOICE] "You must take a vacation. You must have fun. You must enjoy life."
"Prenez des vacances. Amusez-vous. Profitez."
I don't think you have a good handle on dictatorships.
Tu n'as pas saisi le concept de la dictature.
Sheldon, everybody takes vacations.
Tout le monde prend des vacances.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] One time, they tried to make Richard Feynman take a vacation.
Même Richard Feynman a dû en prendre.
But he chose instead to expand his mind and learn something new.
Mais il a choisi d‘élargir son esprit.
He went to work in his friend's biology lab.
Dans le labo de son ami.
Richard Feynman was a famous American physicist...
C‘était un physicien américain
...part of the Manhattan Project.
qui faisait partie du projet Manhattan.
Everyone in the world of science knows who Richard Feynman was.
Le monde dela science le connaît.
Yeah, now you do too.
Et toi aussi, maintenant.
Isn't thatjust Feynman's idea?
Ce n‘est pas l'idée de Feynman ?
Ten seconds ago you never heard of him, now you're an expert.
Il y a dix secondes tu le connaissais a peine.
-Hey. -Hey, you.
- Salut.
That your laundry? You have six things in there.
C‘est ton linge sale ? Il n‘y a rien.
I didn't have any quarters.
Je n‘avais pas de monnaie.
So I've been sneaking stuff into other people's loads all day.
Alors, j'ai planqué mes Vêtements dans les paniéres des autres.
If I tell you something, you promise not to tell anybody?
J'ai un secret mais promets de ne rien dire.
Doesn't matter what I say, you're gonna tell me anyway.
Peu importe. Tu finiras par le dire.
Wha--? That is not true.
C‘est faux.
Bernadette wants a prenup.
Bernadette veut un contrat de mariage.
That's rough.
C‘est d u r.
lfl became a famous movie star and we got married...
Si j‘étais une grande actrice,
-...you wouldn't sign a prenup? -Heh, absolutely not.
- tu ne signerais pas ? - Non.
If I'm gonna be at home with the kids...
Si j‘étais coincé àla maison
...while you're on location cheating on me with Ryan Gosling...
alors que tu me trompes avec Ryan Gosling sur un plateau,
...then Leonard gots to get paid.
Leonard doit être payé.
So do you think about us getting married?
Tu penses à notre mariage ?
I think about a lot of things.
A beaucoup de choses.
I think about us getting married, about us breaking up.
Notre mariage, notre rupture.
Once in a while, I think about how I didn't leave a note on that Mercedes | dinged...
Au fait de ne pas avoir laissé de mot sur la Mercedes
...but then I have a glass of wine and it passes.
que j'ai emboutie mais j'ai vite oublié.
Joke all you want, but you think about it.
Tu peux plaisanter mais tu y penses.
Well, tell you one thing, if I ever do get married, no Klingon invitations.
Si jamais on se marie, pas de faire-part en Klingon.
Good luck catching a man with that attitude.
Bonne chance pour trouver un homme comme ça.
Boy, oh, boy, this vacation is off to a wonderful start.
Ces vacances commencent trés bien.
The smell of formaldehyde.
L‘odeur du formaldéhyde,
The whir of the centrifuge.
Ie ronronnement de la centrifugeuse,
The distant chatter of lab animals being dispatched for dissection.
le bruit lointain des animaux préparés pour être disséqués.
I'm excited to work with my boyfriend. It's romantic.
Je suis ravie de travailler avec mon petit ami.
Way to kill the mood.
Voilà comment tuer l‘ambiance.
Come on, Sheldon. We can be like Marie Curie and her husband, Pierre...
On pourrait être comme Marie Curie et Pierre, son mari,
...who spent their days working side by side...
qui ont travaillé côte à côte,
...bathed in the glow of their love and the radium that ultimately killed her.
baignés dans leur amour et le radium qui afini par la tuer.
Screw Beauty and the Beast, that's the love story Disney should tell.
A bas La Belle et la Bête, voilà l'histoire de Disney.
Okay. What do we start with?
Par quoi on commence ?
Maybe, uh, splicing some genes. Clone a sheep.
Coller quelques gènes, cloner un mouton...
Perhaps, uh, grow a human ear on a mouse's back?
Faire pousser une oreille sur le dos d‘une souris ?
[AS MICKEY MOUSE] "Ha, ha! I'm a freak."
"Je suis un monstre."
Well, I'm gonna be doing some brain stem histology...
Pendant que je fais un peu d‘histologie,
...while you put yourself on the business end of a sponge...
mets—toi àla recherche d‘une éponge
...and wash those beakers.
pour laver ces tubes.
Wash those b-- Oh, I get it.
Laver ces... Ah, j'ai pigé.
Little hazing for the new fellow. Yeah. Better keep an eye out for, what...
C‘est un bizutage. Je dois faire attention
...shoe polish on the microscope...
au cirage sur le microscope
...or mad cow disease in my grilled cheese sandwich?
ou àla vache folle dans mon sandwich ?
No, I just need those beakers washed. Hippity-hop, quick like a bunny.
Non. J'ai besoin que tu les laves. Et fais Vite.
Excuse me, you have Dr. Sheldon Cooper in your lab.
Tu as le Dr. Cooper dans ton labo.
You're gonna make him do the dishes?
Tu veux qu'il fasse la vaisselle ?
That's like asking the Incredible Hulk to open a pickle jar.
Comme demander a Hulk d'ouvrir un pot de cornichons.
Sheldon, you've never worked in a lab like this before.
Tu n'as jamais travaillé dans un labo.
You have no experience in the field of biology.
Tu n'as aucune expérience en biologie.
l have plenty of experience in biology.
J'en ai plein.
I bought a Tamagotchi in 1998...
J'ai acheté un Tamagotchi en 1998
...and it's still alive. Let's do this.
et il est toujours en vie. D'accord ?
Where's Howard?
Où est Howard ?
No, "Hi, Raj," no, "How are you, Raj?"
Pas de ”Salut, Raj" ?
Just straight to, "Where's the other white guy?"
Juste "Où est l‘homme blanc ?"
I'm sorry.
Pardon.
So, listen, I heard something about him. Can you keep it between us?
J'ai appris quelque chose. Tu peux le garder pour toi ?
...I thought Americans really gossiped around the water cooler.
je croyais que vous parliez devant la fontaine à eau.
I hung out there for a month, but the only gossip I heard...
J‘y ai passé un mois mais le seul potin quej'ai entendu
...was about some creepy guy hanging out by the water cooler.
concernait un drôle de type collé àla fontaine.
Bernadette wants to get a prenup.
Bernadette veut un contrat.
Oh, that's a shame. He's gonna be devastated.
C‘est honteux. Il va être dévasté.
I never know what to do in these situations.
J'ignore ce qu'il faut faire.
-Should I give him a heads up? -Hmm.
Je dois lui dire ?
I'm gonna give you the advice I yell at the TV...
Je vais te donner un conseil,
...when the Bachelor is handing out roses.
le même que je crie au célibataire avec les roses.
Follow your heart.
Ecoute ton cœur.
Check it out.
Regardez !
Look at the size of that Rice Krispie Treat. Same price, ha, ha.
Regardez la taille de cette gaufre ! Pour le même prix.
Ahem, hey, Howard, I need to tell you something.
Je dois te parler.
I know, it's not on my wedding diet. I don't care.
Je sais. Ça ne respecte pas mon régime pré-mariage.
Listen, I heard that Bernadette's thinking about asking you for a prenup.
On m‘a dit que Bernadette voulait faire un contrat de mariage.
A prenup?
Un contrat ?
What are you gonna do?
Que vas-tu faire ?
I don't know.
Aucune idée.
Follow your heart.
Ecoute ton cœur.
You know what? It's not a big deal.
Ce n‘est pas grand-chose.
I mean, she makes more money than me.
Elle gagne plus que moi.
She wants to protect her financial interests.
Elle veut protéger ses intérêts financiers.
-lt's completely reasonable. -Good, that's a healthy attitude.
- C‘est normal. - Bonne réaction.
Actually, it's good for both of us. I have assets to protect too.
C‘est bien pour nous deux. J'ai des biens à protéger.
Like what?
Comme quoi ?
Well, I've got some rare comic books.
J'ai des livres rares.
You know, the Vespa's almost paid off.
Ma Vespa est bientôt payé.
Ma and l have a primo double cemetery plot at Mt. Sinai...
Ma mère et moi avons une concession au cimetière
...right near the guy who played Mr. Roper on Three's Company.
juste a côté du type qui jouait M. Roper.
Mr. Roper's dead?
M. Roper est mort ?
You can'tjust spring that on a guy.
Tu ne peux pas parler de quelqu'un comme ça.
Here you go.
Tiens.
This is now the only lab with glassware washed by a man with two doctorates...
Le seul labo où les tubes sont lavés par un homme avec deux doctorats
...and a restraining order signed by Carl Sagan.
et une ordonnance restrictive signée par Carl Sagan.
Soap spots. Wash them again.
Des taches. Recommence.
You're being ridiculous. Those are perfectly clean.
Tu es ridicule. Ils sont parfaitement propres.
This beaker used to contain cerebrospinal fluid...
Ils ont contenu du liquide céphalo-rachidien
...from an elephant that died of syphilis.
d'un éléphant mort dela syphilis.
If it's, in fact, perfectly clean, drink from it.
S‘ils sont propres, bois dans l'un d'eux.
Biologists are mean.
Les biologistes sont méchants.
Perhaps this task will be a little bit more up your alley.
Cette tâche sera plus a ta convenance.
I need you to count the bacteria spores on these petri dishes.
J'ai besoin que tu comptes les spores présentes.
There was something wrong with that detergent.
Le détergent était bizarre.
-That was way too bubbly. -l'm sure it was.
- Trop de mousse. - Sûrement.
I intend to write that soap company a strongly-worded letter.
J‘écrirai a la société une lettre bien détaillée.
Yeah, good for you. Now start counting.
Bien. Maintenant, compte.
You know what this place needs?
Tu sais ce qu'il faudrait ?
A suggestion box.
Une boite à suggestions.
Three hundred sixty-six. Three hundred sixty-seven.
Trois cent soixante-six. Trois cent soixante—sept.
How's it going?
Ça se passe bien ?
How's counting going?
Tu me demandes si je sais compter ?
When lwas in kindergarten...
Ala maternelle,
...l recited pi to athousand places for the school talent show.
j'ai récité les décimales de Pi pour le concours de talents.
-I think I got this. -Great.
- Je peux y arriver. - Super.
Aw, nuts.
Mince.
One.
Un.
This is preposterous.
C‘est stupide.
You're giving me these tasks because you're afraid...
Tu me donnes ces tâches car tu as peur
...if you give me anything meaningful to do, I'll show you up.
que je sois meilleur que toi dans les tâches importantes.
Really? Is that what you think?
C‘est ce que tu crois ?
Yes, that's what I think.
En effet.
And I'm super smart, so it's probably true.
Je suis super intelligent. C‘est sûrement vrai.
Hey, I've been training in the field of neurobiology for 12 years.
Je fais dela neurobiologie depuis 12 ans.
You've been here three hours and you spent one of them in the bathroom.
Tu es la depuis trois heures dont une passée aux W.C.
Well, I'm sorry, it takes me a while to get things going on an unfamiliar toilet.
C‘est le temps qu'il me faut quand je ne les connais pas.
I've given you the simplest things to do and you haven't done one of them right.
Je t'ai donné des choses simples et tu les as mal faites.
That's because I'm not being challenged.
Car ce n‘est pas excitant.
It's the same reason Einstein failed math.
C‘est pour ça que Einstein a échoué en maths.
Maybe the math was too bubbly for him.
Ça faisait trop de bulles.
You think you're doing science by cutting up that brain?
Tu crois faire dela science comme ça ?
They could do the same at Ouiznos.
On fait pareil au restau.
And they'd offer to toast it for me too.
Et ils offrent de le rôtir pour moi.
Okay, smart guy.
Trés bien.
I'm about to remove the locus coeruleus, which is incredibly delicate work.
Je suis sur le point de retirer le locus cœruleus.
Have at it.
Vas-y.
All right.
D‘accord.
I'm no stranger to a little gray matter.
Je connais bien la matière grise.
Locus coeruleus.
Locus cœruleus.
You're getting warmer. It is indeed in the brain.
Tu chauffes. C‘est dans le cerveau.
Hope your hands are steady. It's the width of a single hair.
Ne tremble pas. Ça fait la largeur d'un cheveu.
But this is just biology, so it's no problem for a genius like you.
Ce n‘est que dela biologie. Facile pour un génie.
It's not. I will have you know in the field of physics we work...
Pour ta gouverne, en physique, nous travaillons
...with particles so small they make fatjokes about the locus coeruleus...
avec des particules si petites qu‘elles rient du locus cœruleus.
...ie, when your locus coeruleus sits around the house...
Comme quand le locus cœruleus est chez vous,
...it sits around the house.
il est chez vous.
-Are we nervous, Dr. Cooper? -No.
- Tu es nerveux ? - Non.
What you see is a man trembling with confidence.
Je tremble avec confiance.
Does the locus coeruleus normally bleed that much?
Le locus cœruleus saigne autant que ça ?
No, but your thumb does.
Non, mais ton pouce, oui.
Oh, dear.
Oh, mon Dieu.
Yeah, you're a biologist.
C‘est ça, tu es biologiste.
What are you doing here?
Que fais-tu ici ?
I'm on vacation.
Je suis en vacances.
Social convention dictates that I let my hair down at a local watering hole.
La convention sociale veut que j‘aille au point d‘eau local.
Social convention is stupid.
La convention sociale est stupide.
What happened to your thumb?
Et ton pouce ?
Yeah, I have ten fingers and ten toes.
J'ai dix doigts et dix orteils.
If I tell you a story about each of them, we'll be here all day. Let's move on.
Je ne vais pas te parler de chacun d‘entre eux, si ?
-What can I get you? -Ah.
Que voulez-vous ?
Seeing as I'm on vacation, a piï¬a colada seems appropriate.
Comme je suis en vacances, je prends une piña colada.
Extra pineapple slices, extra whipped cream...
Supplément d‘ananas, supplément de crème,
...extra cherries, extra umbrellas, and, uh, hold the rum.
supplément de cerises et de parapluies et ralenti sur le rhum.
Don't let me have too many of those.
Ne me laisse pas trop boire.
Hey. What are you guys doing here?
Que faites-vous la ?
No and no.
Non et non.
Everything okay with you and Bernadette?
Tout va bien avec Bernadette ?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Oui, bien sûr.
-You and Amy? Good? -Oh, better than good.
- Et toi et Amy ? - Mieux que ça.
Those girls text me every detail of their lives as it happens.
Ces filles m'envoient tous les détails par textos.
I'm not signing a prenup.
Je ne signerai rien.
All right, Wolowitz, listen up. You sign anything she puts in front of you.
Ecoute—moi bien. Tu vas signer tout ce qu'elle veut.
You are the luckiest man alive.
Tu es un veinard.
If you let her go, there is no way you can find anyone else.
Si tu la laisses partir, tu seras seul.
Speaking on behalf of all women, it is not gonna happen, we had a meeting.
Je parle au nom de toutes les femmes.
And you.
Et toi.
A grown man fainting at the sight of a little blood.
Un adulte qui s'évanouit pour un peu de sang.
Excuse me, this is a fairly substantial wound. You--
C‘est une blessure très profonde. Tu…
Amy. Amy.
Amy...
What do you want?
Que veux-tu ?
l was kind of hoping I could continue vacationing in your laboratory.
J'espérais pouvoir continuer mes vacances ici.
After all, I did book the whole week.
Après tout, j'ai réservé toute la semaine.
Do you honestly think you can just waltz back in here...
Tu crois honnêtement que tu peux revenir
...after the way you behaved yesterday?
après ton comportement d'hier ?
l was not myself. I had lost a lot of thumb blood.
Je n‘étais pas moi—mème. J'ai perdu beaucoup de sang de pouce.
-That's not an apology. -That is your opinion.
- Ce n‘est pas une excuse. - C‘est ton avis.
I want a real apology.
Je veux de vraies excuses.
-l'm sorry that you weren't able to-- -No.
- Je suis désolé que tu n‘aies... - Non.
-That my genius got--
- Que mon génie...
-That the soap was so-- -Sheldon.
- Que le savon... - Sheldon.
Fine.
D‘accord.
Sorry.
Je suis désolé.
You're forgiven.
Tu es pardonné.
Now, if you wanna stay...
Si tu veux rester,
...get started on those beakers. They're still dirty from yesterday.
commence par les tubes. Ils sont toujours sales.
Next year, I'm going to Epcot.
L'an prochain, j'irai à Disney.
Are you mad at me?
Tu es en colère après moi ?
I just wish you would've come to me...
Je suis triste que tu ne m'aies rien dit
...so I didn't have to hear it through the nerd-vine.
et que je l'aie appris par un polard.
So, what are we gonna do?
Qu'allons-nous faire ?
-You really want me to sign a prenup? -I don't know.
- Tu veux vraiment que je signe ? - Aucune idée.
My dad's pretty insistent on it, though.
Mon père y tient beaucoup.
Why don't I talk to your dad?
Et si je lui parlais ?
-Man to man. -Really?
- D‘homme a homme. - Vraiment ?
-Oh, that'd be so great. Heh. -Done.
- Excellente idée. - D‘accord.
I should probably give you a heads up about a couple things.
Je vais te donner quelques conseils avant.
Even though he's retired from the police force, he still carries his gun.
Même s'il est a la retraite, il porte toujours son arme.
But don't worry, he won't shoot it. It's more of a fashion statement.
Il ne tirera pas. C‘est plus pour faire genre.
And just to be safe, when you talk to him...
Pour ne prendre aucun risque,
...don't bring up Jimmy Carter, gardeners...
ne parle pas de Jimmy Carter, de jardiniers,
...foreign people, homosexuals, Sean Penn, Vatican II, gun control...
d'étrangers, d'homosexuels, de Sean Penn, du pape,
...organic food, the designated hitter rule...
de nourriture organique, de base—ball,
...recycling or the fact that you're Jewish.
de recyclage ou du fait que tu es juif.
Got it, got it. Will you e-mail me that list, heh?
J'ai compris.
So the thing to watch for, if he's shouting at you, you're okay.
S'il te crie dessus, c‘est bon signe.
But if he starts to get real quiet...
S'il reste silencieux,
...leave as quickly as you can without making eye contact.
pars le plus vite possible sans le regarder dans les yeux.
Not in a straight line, throw some zigs and zags in there.
Pas tout droit mais en faisant des zigzags.
You know, this isn't that pressing.
Tu sais, ça ne presse pas.
Why don't I talk to him about it in May, heh?
Je pourrais lui parler en mai.
In May you're gonna be on the International Space Station.
Mais tu seras dans la station spatiale internationale.
They got a phone.
Ils ont le téléphone.
[English - us - an]
[French]